Guide to the Stewart M. Brandborg Papers 1932-2000
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Stewart M. Brandborg Papers
1932-2000
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 699
Stewart M. Brandborg, 1925-
45.0 linear feet
This collection consists of the professional papers of environmental activist Stewart M. Brandborg. Brandborg served as Executive Director of The Wilderness Society from 1964-1977 and his papers include correspondence, research files and other documents from his time with that agency. Other materials cover his work with the National Wildlife Federation, the National Park Service, Wilderness Watch, and Friends of the Bitterroot (Montana.)
Biographical Note
Stewart M. Brandborg was born in Lewiston, Idaho, in February of 1925. His father, Guy M. "Brandy" Brandborg, was the assistant to the forest supervisor on the Nez Perce National Forest. In 1935, the Brandborg family moved to Montana where Guy Brandborg would serve as the forest supervisor for the Bitterroot National Forest for twenty years. In 1943, Stewart Brandborg began university studies at Montana State University in Missoula (now called The University of Montana.) It was here that Stewart met his future wife, Anna Vee Mather. Brandborg graduated in 1947 with a bachelor’s of science in wildlife technologies. He and Anna Vee were married in 1949 and would later have 5 children.
In the late 1940s Brandborg conducted pioneering mountain goat research while working for the Montana Department of Fish and Game. In 1949, while studying for his Master’s degree in Forestry at The University of Idaho, he was a research fellow at the Idaho Cooperative Wildlife Research Unit. Upon graduation (1951), Brandborg conducted research and management investigations on the mountain goat, elk, and other big game species with the Idaho Department of Fish and Game, where he worked through 1953.
In 1954, Brandborg and his family moved to Washington DC where he had taken a position with the National Wildlife Federation as an assistant conservation director. While with the Federation, Brandborg worked with local conservation leaders on proposed dams on the Clearwater River in Idaho. He assisted in extending the Keep America Beautiful program to a state level and oversaw the publication and circulation of conservation literature to the public. In 1956, while still with the National Wildlife Federation, Brandborg was elected to the governing board of The Wilderness Society and in 1960 he was hired by The Wilderness Society as associate executive director. After the death of the director, Howard Zahniser, in 1964, Brandborg became the director of The Wilderness Society.
While at The Wilderness Society, Brandborg faced many challenges and a changing environmental movement. He placed a strong emphasis on working with local groups on conservation issues and stressed the importance of grassroots volunteers. He worked on proposing and supporting wilderness for designation under the newly minted National Wilderness Preservation Act passed in 1964. He also lent the support of The Wilderness Society to stopping a proposal for a Trans-Alaskan pipeline that threatened wilderness and wildlife in Alaska beginning in the late 1960s and the early 1970s. Although the pipeline was eventually built, the efforts of The Wilderness Society led to greater environmental regulations on the pipeline and the eventual declaration of over 100 million acres of parks, refuges, and wild rivers in Alaska. After an acrimonious departure from The Wilderness Society in January of 1977, Brandborg worked as special assistant to the director of The National Park Service until 1981. Iin this position Brandborg was responsible for the development of citizen participation programs to foster communication between The National Park Service and local citizens. In 1982, Brandborg became the national coordinator for The Regional Environmental Leadership Conference Series. Brandborg developed training materials and organized regional conferences to train new leaders in the environmental movement. He worked with The Leadership Series until he left Washington to return to Montana in 1986.
Brandborg returned to Montana's Bitterroot Valley and served as president of the Friends of the Bitterroot from 1988-1990, and with Bitterrooters for Planning. In 1998 he served on the board of directors of Wilderness Watch. He continued to work on environmental issues from his home in Hamilton, Montana, until his death on April 14, 2018.
The Stewart M. Brandborg Papers have been organized into eight series arranged by the periods in Brandborg’s professional career. The majority of the series have been further subdivided into an administrative subseries and a subject file subseries, reflecting the order in which they were maintained by Brandborg. The largest series in this collection relates to Brandborg's time with The Wilderness Society and includes planning documents, committee minutes, and extensive correspondence files.
Of particular interest within this collection are documents and congressional testimony related to the recommendation of new wilderness areas into the National Wilderness Preservation System signed into law in 1986, as well as documents related to the trans-Alaskan pipeline in the late 1960s and early 1970s. Also included are documents related to the Park Service's Citizen Participation Program which Brandborg helped develop and implement in the late 1970s.
This collection does not contain personal or family papers or photographs, although some of the files include correspondence from Stewart Brandborg's father, Guy M. Brandborg. The collection contains only a small number of materials related to the work Brandborg has done since his return to Montana from Washington D.C. in 1986.
This collection has been divided into eight series:
Series I: Rocky Mountain Goat Research, 1932-1953, 0.75 linear ft.
Series II: Idaho Department of Fish and Game, 1932-1954, 2.25 linear ft.
Subseries 1: Administration, 1949-1954, 0.25 linear ft.
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1932-1954, 2.0 linear ft.
Series III: The National Wildlife Federation, 1946-1960, 3.25 linear ft.
Subseries 1: Administration, 1954-1960, 1.0 linear ft.
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1946-1960, 2.25 linear ft.
Series IV: The Wilderness Society, 1930-1977, 28.0 linear ft.
Subseries 1: Administration, 1954-1976, 2.25 linear ft.
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1930-1977, 25.75 linear ft.
Series V: Citizens Action Center, 1976-1977, 0.5 linear ft.
Series VI: National Park Service, 1976-1982, 4.5 linear ft.
Subseries 1: Administration, 1976-1981, 3.25 linear ft.
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1976-1982, 1.25 linear ft.
Series VII: National Leadership Development Conference Series, 1981-1988, 5.25 linear ft.
Subseries 1: Administration, 1981-1986, 5.0 linear ft.
Subseries 2: Subject Files, 1981-1988, 0.25 linear ft.
Series VIII: Friends of the Bitterroot and Wilderness Watch, 1984-2000, 0.5 linear ft.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
This collection was maintained by Stewart Brandborg until its donation to the Archives.
This collection was donated to the Archives by Stewart Brandborg in several accessions from 2005-2006.
Most bound monographs and congressional records and reports were seperated from the collection and placed in the Library's general stacks.
The Archives holds the papers of Stewart Brandborg's father, Guy M. Brandborg (Mss 691) as well as several oral history interviews with Stewart Brandborg. The Denver Public Library's Western History and Genealogy Department holds a substantial collection of Wilderness Society records.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Brandborg, G. M.(Guy Mathew), 1893-1977--Correspondence; Brandborg, Stewart M.--Archives
Idaho. Fish and Game Dept.; Montana. Dept. of Fish and Game; United States. National Park Service; Friends of the Bitterroot; National Wildlife Federation; University of Idaho. Idaho Cooperative Wildlife Research Unit; University of Montana--Missoula--Alumni and alumnae; Wilderness Society (U.S.)
Trans-Alaska Pipeline (Alaska)--Environmental aspects
Conservation of natural resources--Montana--Bitterroot River Valley $xSocieties, etc.; Conservation of natural resources--United States; Environmentalism--United States--Societies, etc.; Wildlife conservation--Law and legislation--United States; Wildlife conservation--United States--Societies, etc.
Alaska; Idaho; Montana; Environmental Activism; Environmental Conditions
Conservationists--United States; Environmentalists--United States
- Rocky Mountain Goat Research, 1932-1953; Series I:; 0.75 linear ft.
  This series contains subject files typically consisting of correspondence, memos, clippings, and/or notes.
  - Drafts of Thesis Introduction, undated (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Federal Aid in Wildlife Restoration Act, 1941-1950 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Field Notes on the Mountain Goat, Sun Butte National Forest, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Graduate Research, 1948 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Life History Observations of the Rocky Mountain Goat, Draft, 1948 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Life History Observations of the Rocky Mountain Goat, Draft, undated (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Montana Department of Fish and Game Mountain Goat Data, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Montana Fish and Game Department, Original Goat Report, 1947 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Mountain Goat, 1948 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Mountain Goat Data, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Salmon River, Originals, 1949 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Mountain Goat Food Habits, 1947 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Mountain Goat Quarterly Reports and Others, 1948 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Mountain Goat, Flathead-Sun River, Census, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Report of the Middle Fork Game Study, 1932 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Report of Wildlife Studies in Jasper, Banff, and Yoho National Parks, 1944 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - South Dakota Mountain Goat Report, 1949 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - The Montana Study, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 2/6)
- Idaho Department of Fish and Game, 1932-1954; Series II:; 2.25 linear ft.
  This series is arranged into two subseries. Subseries 1: Administration includes Brandborg’s monthly reports, internal correspondence, and project reports. Subseries 2: Subject Files consists mainly of field notes on observations of big game and photographic records.
  - Administration, 1949-1954; Subseries 1:; 0.25 linear ft
    - Administration General, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Literature Circulation, 1953 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Operational and Project Reports, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - W.L. Pengelly Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - D.R. Smith Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Summary of Monthly Activities, Stewart M. Brandborg, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Summary of Monthly Activities, Stewart M. Brandborg, 1953 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Toastmasters, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Subject Files, 1932-1954; Subseries 2:; 2 linear ft.
    - Adult Education Association, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Age Composition Study of Mountain Goats in the Selkirk Management Area, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Annual Spring Trend Counts, Selkirk Management Area, 1952 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Big Game Reports and Papers, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Distribution and Census of Mountain Goats in the Selkirk Management Area, 1951 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Grazing Bill, Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Historical Distribution and Population, Selkirk Management Area, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Idaho Goat Studies, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Management Study of the Rocky Mountain Goat, Quarterly and Progress Reports, 1952 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Salmon River, Originals, 1950 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Salmon River, Originals, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Salmon River, Originals, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Selkirk Mountains, Originals, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Selway River, Originals, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Mountain Goat Field Notes, Selway River, Typewritten, 1950 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Mountain Goat Publication, 1953 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Mountain Goat Trend Count Areas in the Selkirk Management Area, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Mountain Goat, Authors and Inquiry, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Other Species, Selkirk Management Area, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Plans for Harvest and Management, Selkirk Management Area, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Public Domain, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Public Relations, Sportsmen's Clubs, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Range Condition Research, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Salmon River General Field Notes, Originals, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Salmon River General Field Notes, Originals, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Salmon River General Field Notes, Typewritten, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Salmon River Photo Transect No. 1 and Photo Plots, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Salmon River Watershed Historical Range and District, Job Completion Reports-Census and Distribution, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Selkirk Management Area Photographic Records, 1951 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Selkirk Mountains General Field Notes, Originals, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Selway River General Field Notes, Originals, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - D.R. Smith, Big Horn Sheep Reports, Quarterly and Completion, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Soil Stability Guide, 1953 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - State Reports Notes, 1953 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Statewide Mountain Goat Distribution Map and Population Estimates, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Vegetation and Forage Studies on Mountain Goat, Selkirk Management Act, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 5/11)
- The National Wildlife Federation, 1946-1960; Series III:; 3.25 linear ft.
  This series has been divided into two subseries. Subseries 1: Administration contains internal documents including budgetary information, meeting agendas and notes, and monthly reports. Subseries 2: Subject Files contains primarily correspondence, notes, clippings, congressional testimony, and speech information.
  - Administration, 1954-1960; Subseries 1; 1 linear ft.
    - Agendas for Board of Directors Meetings, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Annual Meeting, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Board and Annual Meetings, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Budget and Fiscal, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Conservation Director Reports, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Executive Director Monthly Reports, Field Meeting Schedule, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Manual, 1959 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Meeting Opening Statements, 1960 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Project Statements and Evaluations, Leadership, 1960 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Report of Stewart Brandborg, Assistant Conservation Director, 1955 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Reports and Papers, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Requests, Leave, Executive Director Memos, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Salaries, etc., 1957-1959 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Terminated Policies, Connecticut General Life Insurance Company, 1959 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Travel Expenses, 1959 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Subject Files, 1946-1960; Subseries 2; 2.25 linear ft.
    - Aiken Grazing Bill, S. 2548, 1954 (Box-folder 6/13-14)
    - Bruce's Eddy Dam Proposal, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Bureau of Land Management and Fish and Wildlife Service Long Range Program, 1960 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Chesapeake and Ohio Canal, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Clippings, Brochures, Directories, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 7/4-5)
    - Columbia River Basin Fish and Wildlife Reports, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Committee of 100 on the Federal City, 1960 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Conservation Education Pamphlets, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Conservation News, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Conservation News, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Conservation Report, 1956 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Conservation Report, 84th Congress, 2nd Session, 1956 (Box-folder 8/1-2)
    - Conservation Report, 85th Congress, 1st and 2nd Session, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8/3-5)
    - Conservation Report, 85th Congress, 2nd Session, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 8/6-7)
    - Educational Policy, 1958 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Educational Program, 1954 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Endangered Wildlife Publications, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Federal Timber Sales Policies, 1946-1958 (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Grazing Bill, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Information Specialists, Television Programs, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 9/3-4)
    - International Union for Conservation of Nature Leaflets, Soil and Water Conservation, 1959 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Jaycee Conservation Commission, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 9/6-7)
    - Jaycee Conservation Committee, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Jaycee Conservation Information, 1959 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Jaycee Conservation Program, 1959 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Joint Legislative Conference, 1960 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Leadership Training, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Letters to be Sent, 1954 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Meeting of Conservation Roundtable, 1960 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Montana Cooperative Wildlife Research Unit, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Montana Educational Program, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 10/1-3)
    - National Wilderness Preservation System, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1956 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1957 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1957 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1958 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1960 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - National Wildlife Week, 1960 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - National Youth Conservation Council, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Nature Center for Young America, 1960 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Nontechnical Book on Outdoor Recreation, 1958 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Opposition to Bruce's Eddy Dam, Columbia River, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Pamphlets, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Ravalli County Fish and Wildlife Association, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Salmon River, 1959 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Speech Material, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Speech Material, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Speeches, Miscellaneous, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Stewart Brandborg Pocket Calendar and Notes, 1958 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Subcommittees on Park Proposals, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - The Conservation Directory, 1958 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Watershed Pamphlets, 1960 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Western Association of State Game and Fish Commissioners Conference, 1960 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Wilderness Bill, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 12/9-10)
    - Yellowstone Lake Boating, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Youth Conservation Corps, 1959 (Box-folder 12/12)
- The Wilderness Society, 1930-1977; Series IV; 28.0 linear ft.
  This series is arranged into two subseries. Subseries 1: Administration contains materials regarding staff meetings, budgets, notes, internal memos and correspondence, staff recruitment and planning, and The Wilderness Society Executive Committee meetings. Subseries 2: Subject Files contains correspondence, notes, clippings, congressional testimony, and speech information. Of particular interest are memos, notes, correspondence, and Congressional Testimony given on areas proposed for entry in the Wilderness Preservation System and the fight against the Trans-Alaskan Pipeline.
  - Administration, 1954-1976; Subseries 1; 2.25 linear ft.
    - Administrative Division, Job Descriptions, undated (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Annual Meeting-Check if in the right series, 1975 (Box-folder 13/2-3)
    - Appendices L and M, The Wilderness Society Manual, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 13/4-5)
    - Applications/Resumes, 1975 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Budget, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 13/7-8)
    - Budget Cuts, 1974 (Box-folder 13/9-12)
    - Budget Plan, 1975 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Budget Planning, 1969 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Budget Planning, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Calls, Officers and Executive Committee, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Cash Reports, 1976 (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Check Request and Travel Forms, undated (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Consultant and Grant in Aid Review, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Consultant Field Staff, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Consultant Plans, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Consultant Reports from Colorado, 1975 (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Contact Lists, 1974 (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Council Nominations, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Current Council Memberships, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Current Council Memberships, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 15/1-2)
    - Denver Staff Coordinator, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Denver Staff Meeting, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Director's Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Division Leaders Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Divisional Leaders Meeting Notes, 1975 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Editorial and Public Information Division Job Descriptions, undated (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Employment File, 1964 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Executive Committee and Executive Council, Memos and Correspondence, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Executive Committee Financial Reports, 1975 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Executive Committee Notes, 1974 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Executive Staff and Committee, Internal Memos, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Expense Notes, undated (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Field Leadership Schedule, 1974 (Box-folder 15/15)
    - Field Staff and Consultant Weekly Activity Report, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 15/16)
    - Field Staff and Representative Weekly Activity Report, 1968 (Box-folder 15/17)
    - Field Staff and Representative Weekly Activity Report, 1974 (Box-folder 15/18)
    - Field Staff and Wilderness Consultants Weekly Activity Report, 1969 (Box-folder 15/19)
    - Financial Planning, Wendell Nance, 1974 (Box-folder 15/20)
    - Funding Committee, 1973 (Box-folder 15/21)
    - Income Projects, 1974 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Investment Program, 1974 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Issues-Council Meeting, 1976 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Major Issues Requiring Resolution by the Conference Committee, 1973 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Memos and Miscellaneous Internal Documents, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Clifton Merritt, Denver Office Cuts, 1974 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Clifton Merritt, Internal Memos and Activity Reports, 1966-1975 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Clifton Merritt, Plans, Notes, 1974 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Organizational Charts, undated (Box-folder 16/10)
    - Organizational Development, Charts and Recruitment, 1975 (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Organizational Recruitment, 1975 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Payroll and Salary Changes, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Personal Expense Claims, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 16/14-15)
    - Plans Coordinator, Division Programs, Jim Deane, 1975 (Box-folder 16/16)
    - Post-Dismissal Letter, 1976 (Box-folder 16/17)
    - Program Objectives, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 16/18)
    - Recruitment, 1974 (Box-folder 16/19)
    - Regulations, 1964 (Box-folder 16/20)
    - Staff Meeting Notes, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 16/21)
    - Staff Meeting Notes and Minutes, 1973 (Box-folder 16/22)